A Guide to the Blanchette H. Rockefeller Papers FA107
Rockefeller Archive Center
Blanchette H. Rockefeller papers
1745, 1884-1994, bulk 1910-1994
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker
Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.)
FA107
45 Cubic Feet 82 Boxes
82 Boxes, 45 cubic feet
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Material in the Rockefeller family collections that provides the names, correspondence, or activities of living members of the Rockefeller family, and/or documents the net wealth of any Rockefeller family members, is restricted from scholarly access. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement note
The papers of Blanchette H. Rockefeller are divided into the following seven series:
Series 1 - Hooker and Ferry Families Files, 1745, 1884-1992 Series 2 - Rockefeller Family Files, 1932-1991 Series 3 - Subject Files, 1933-1994 Series 4 - Museum of Modern Art Files, 1951-1992 Series 5 - Political Files, 1961-1992 Series 6 - Restricted material Series 7 - Photographs
Biographical/Historical note
Blanchette Ferry Hooker was born in New York City on October 2, 1909, the youngest of the four daughters of Blanche Ferry, an heiress to the Ferry seed fortune, and Elon Huntington Hooker, an engineer and president of the Hooker Electro-Chemical Company. From 1918 through 1927 she was a student at Miss Chapin's School for Girls. During her childhood Blanchette acquired a nickname, "Hookie," by which she would be known to family and close friends throughout her life.
In 1927 she began her studies at Vassar College, which culminated with an A.B. degree in music in 1931. Blanchette was president of her senior class and was voted the "Most Perfect Lady" as well as the "Most Respected" member of her graduating class. A year later (November 11, 1932) she married John D. Rockefeller 3rd, the eldest of the five sons of John D. Rockefeller Jr., at the Riverside Church in New York City. Together they raised four children. They maintained principal residences in New York City and at Fieldwood Farm in Mt. Pleasant in Westchester County, New York.
Blanchette Rockefeller began her life-long involvement in New York City's charitable and civic activities by joining the Community Service Society in 1933 as a member of its Central Council. She was also a trustee of the Brearley School, Vassar College, and The Juilliard School. Mrs. Rockefeller's lengthy affiliation with the Museum of Modern Art began in 1949 with her role as founding chairman of its Junior Council. She served the museum in various capacities (including two terms as president) until her election as President Emeritus in 1987.
From 1974 to 1980 Mrs. Rockefeller was a member of the National Council on the Humanities. She was appointed to the New York State Council on the Arts in 1979, and was re-appointed in 1981 for a six-year term. In 1985 she was elected to the Board of the Vivian Beaumont Theater. Her memberships included the New York Philharmonic Symphony Society, the English-Speaking Union, the American Federation of Arts, the Riverside Church, and the River Club as well as numerous other leading cultural institutions.
Mrs. Rockefeller shared many of her husband's philanthropic interests. She was a member of the Asia Society, which he founded, as well as a member of both the Society's Gallery Advisory Committee and the Friends of Asia House. She was also a member of the Gallery Committee of the Japan Society and of the American Advisory Committee to the Japan Foundation. Their deep interest in Asia and Asian art had begun in the early 1950s with Mr. Rockefeller's appointment to John Foster Dulles' Peace Treaty Mission to Japan, a country that would become almost a second home to the couple.
Throughout their marriage, Blanchette and John D. Rockefeller 3rd devoted a great deal of time to art collecting. They gradually assembled world-class collections of Asian and American art which were donated to the Asia Society and to San Francisco's DeYoung Museum respectively.
Blanchette Ferry Hooker Rockefeller died from Alzheimer's disease complicated by pneumonia on November 29, 1992, at her home in Mt. Pleasant. She was 83 years old. A memorial service was held at the Riverside Church in New York City on December 4 of that year.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of Blanchette Ferry Hooker Rockefeller (1909-1992), which span the years 1884-1994, document the various roles Mrs. John D. Rockefeller 3rd played in her lifetime, including that of daughter, wife, mother, daughter-in-law, aunt, friend, philanthropist, art collector, and political fundraiser. The papers contain her personal and family correspondence, photographs, and memorabilia as well as the records generated by her philanthropic activities. They provide information on her ancestors; education; relationships with family members, friends, and associates; travels; and on her social concerns and benevolences. While the bulk of the papers deals with Mrs. Rockefeller's lifetime, some items relating to her forebears predate her birth. Due to shared interests and activities in many areas, Mrs. Rockefeller's papers parallel and complement the papers of her husband, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, which are also housed at the Rockefeller Archive Center and which are open to researchers.
Related Archival Materials note
The most significant collections at the Rockefeller Archive Center containing material relevant to the life and work of Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller are all part of the Rockefeller Family Archives. They include the Abby Aldrich Rockefeller papers,which form series Series AA of the Office of the Messrs Rockefeller records; the Nelson A. Rockefeller papers, Personal, Series C.3 Art, Series H Family and Friends, and Series L Projects (under Museums - MoMA); and the John D. Rockefeller 3rd papers.
File Plan note
Former Classification: III 53
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The forty-five cubic feet of material that comprise the Blanchette H. Rockefeller (BHR) Papers were transferred to the Rockefeller Archive Center from the Rockefeller family offices in New York City in five installments from February through April 1995.
Arts; Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker, 1909-1992 -- Political activity; Art -- Collectors and collecting; Art; Philanthropy
- Hooker and Ferry Families Files, 1745, 1884-1992; 53/1; 5 Cubic Feet 11 Boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains personal family correspondence, wills and estate settlement papers, photographs, albums, and biographical and genealogical information regarding Blanchette Rockefeller's parents, siblings, grandparents, and ancestors. Mrs. Rockefeller, a descendant of Massachusetts Colony pastor Thomas Hooker, was the daughter of Elon H. Hooker, a civil engineer and founder of the Hooker Electrochemical Company who was active in Republican politics. A friend of and advisor to Theodore Roosevelt, Elon Hooker was a candidate for the Republican nomination for the governorship of New York in 1920. He was also chairman of the Committee on Internal Trade and Improvements of the Chamber of Commerce of the State of New York. This series contains speeches and articles by Hooker as well as ephemera from his gubernatorial campaign. Material on the history of the electrochemical company will also be found here (box 8).
  Blanchette's mother, Blanche Ferry, was the daughter of the founder of the Detroit-based seed company, D. M. Ferry and Co., a predecessor of the Ferry-Morse Seed Co. (Information on the seed companies, including an 1896 brochure entitled "Extra Early Blanche Ferry Sweet Pea," can be found in box 1 of this series.) Blanche Ferry's wedding to Elon Hooker in 1901 is documented here as well as her role as the mother of four daughters: Barbara, Adelaide, Helen, and Blanchette. Of special interest in these files are the letters written by and about Blanchette during her childhood (box 4). (Note that letters written to Blanche Ferry Hooker upon the engagement and wedding of her daughter Blanchette to John D. Rockefeller 3rd will be found in boxes 26, 50, and 51 of the Subject Series.)
  Additionally, this series provides ample evidence of the deep affection Mrs. Rockefeller had for her sisters and their families. She tended to the needs of various family members, including those of her never-married oldest sister, Barbara, who suffered from mental illness. Mrs. Rockefeller's sister Adelaide married the best-selling novelist John P. Marquand. Her sister Helen, an artist and poet, was first married to Ernest O'Malley, a prominent figure in the Irish Republican movement who began his connection with the cause at the age of 18 during the Easter Week uprising of 1916. Throughout her life Mrs. Rockefeller corresponded with and remained close and attentive to her sisters, nieces, and nephews.
  - Ferry Family - Coat of Arms (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ferry Family - Genealogical Material (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ferry Family - Historical Study, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ferry Family - Coonley, Queene Ferry, 1901-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ferry Family - Faulkner, Elizabeth Ferry Coonley, 1979-1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ferry Family - Ferry, Dexter Mason and Descendants, 1898-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ferry Family - Ferry, Dexter Mason - "86 Years and the Seed Company in Detroit", 1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ferry Family - Ferry, Dexter, 1972-1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ferry Family - Ferry, Edith, 1884-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ferry Family - Ferry, Edith (Hooper), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ferry Family - Ferry, Jean (Davis), 1979, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ferry Family - Ferry, W. Hawkins, 1963-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ferry Family - Ferry Morse Seed Company, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ferry Family - Ferry Morse Seed Company, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ferry Family - Ferry Morse Seed Company, 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Ferry Family - Ferry Morse Seed Company, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Hooker Family - Coat of Arms (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hooker Family - Genealogy, 1935-1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Hooker Family - Historical Material, 1745, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Hooker Family - Correspondence, 1942-1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Hooker Family - Occidental Oil, 1934-1975 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Barbara Ferry - Correspondence, 1916, 1922, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Barbara Ferry - Correspondence, 1939-1951 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Barbara Ferry - Correspondence, 1958-1992 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Barbara Ferry - Trust, 1939-1992 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Barbara Ferry - Trust, 1939-1992 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Barbara Ferry - Trust, 1939-1992 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Barbara Ferry - Trust, 1939-1992 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Barbara Ferry - Trust, 1939-1992 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Wedding to Elon Hooker, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Correspondence About Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, 1910-1913 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Correspondence About Daughters, 1919-1920 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Correspondence to Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, 1919, 1929-1951 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - 82nd Birthday, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Miscellany, 1921-1956 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Death - Condolence Letters to Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Death - Condolence Letters to Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate, 1957-1960 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller Trust, 1957-1991 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller Trust, 1957-1991 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller Trust, 1957-1991 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Ferry-Milfer Trust, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Hooker Employees, 1956-1985 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Legal Papers, 1956-1960 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Legal Papers, 1956-1960 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Legal Papers, 1956-1960 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Legal Papers, 1956-1960 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Legal Papers, 1956-1960 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Marquand and Roelofs, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Metropolitan Opera Gift, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Securities Statements, 1956-1960 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Securities Statements, 1956-1960 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Securities Statements, 1956-1960 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Blanche Ferry - Estate - Securities Statements, 1956-1960 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Elon H. - Correspondence, 1895-1974 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Elon H. - Cornell University Memorial Fellowship Fund, 1965-1972 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Elon H. - Estate Settlement, 1938-1940 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Elon H. - Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1917-1938, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Elon H. - Obituaries, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Elon H. - Speeches and Articles, 1894, 1896, 1915-1937 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Elon H. - Speeches and Articles, 1894, 1896, 1915-1937 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Elon H. - Speeches and Articles - Muscle Shoals Propositions, 1924-1926 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Elon H. - University of Rochester Hooker Fund, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Hooker Family - Hooker, Harry Mix - Tribute Booklet, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Hooker Family - Marquand, Adelaide Hooker, 1932-1963 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Hooker Family - Marquand, Adelaide Hooker - Condolence Letters on Death of, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Hooker Family - Marquand, Adelaide Hooker - Estate, 1963-1989 (Box 9, Folder 69)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted - Confidential material.
  - Hooker Family - Marquand, Adelaide Hooker - Contributions in Memory of, 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Hooker Family - Marquand, Adelaide Hooker - Trusts Under Will of, 1968-1987 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Hooker Family - Marquand, Adelaide Hooker - Trusts Under Will of, 1968-1987 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Hooker Family - Marquand, Adelaide Hooker - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller Trust for Children of, 1976-1982 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Hooker Family - Marquand, Sabina Ferry, 1958-1990 (Box 9, Folder 74)
    Restricted material.
  - Hooker Family - Marquand, Timothy, 1959-1991 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Hooker Family - O'Malley, Cahal Hooker - Correspondence, 1951-1963, 1975-1991 (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - Hooker Family - O'Malley, Cahal Hooker - Correspondence, 1951-1963, 1975-1991 (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - Hooker Family - O'Malley, Cahal Hooker - Report Cards, 1952-1955 (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Hooker Family - O'Malley, Cahal Hooker - Children of, 1966-1989 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - Hooker Family - O'Malley, Cormac K. H., 1979-1992 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Hooker Family - O'Malley, Etain, 1948-1992 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - Hooker Family - Roelofs, Helen Hooker O'Malley, 1971-1993 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Hooker Family - Roelofs, Helen Hooker O'Malley - Correspondence, 1912, 1932-1977 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Hooker Family - Roelofs, Helen Hooker O'Malley - Correspondence, 1912, 1932-1977 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Hooker Family - Roelofs, Helen Hooker O'Malley - Legal and Financial, 1940-1947 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Hooker Family - Roelofs, Helen Hooker O'Malley - Legal and Financial, 1948-1988 (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - Hooker Family - Roelofs, Helen Hooker O'Malley - Legal and Financial, 1948-1988 (Box 11, Folder 87)
  - Hooker Family - Roelofs, Helen Hooker O'Malley - Legal and Financial, 1948-1988 (Box 11, Folder 88)
  - Hooker Family - Roelofs, Helen Hooker O'Malley - Legal and Financial, 1948-1988 (Box 11, Folder 89)
  - Hooker Family - Roelofs, Helen Hooker O'Malley - Ireland Property, 1979-1982 (Box 11, Folder 90)
  - Hooker Family - Roelofs, Helen Hooker O'Malley - Ireland Property, 1979-1982 (Box 11, Folder 91)
  - Hooker Family - Roelofs, Helen Hooker O'Malley - Poetry, 1967-1989 (Box 11, Folder 92)
- Rockefeller Family Files, 1932-1991; 53/2; 0.3 Cubic Feet 1 Box
  This series is composed mostly of letters sent to Mrs. Rockefeller by members of the Rockefeller family. The letters provide evidence of the warm relationships between her and the various family members. Of special interest are the letters between Mrs. Rockefeller and her parents-in-law, Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr., who enthusiastically welcomed Blanchette into their family. Also of note in this series are the letters, postcards, and telegrams sent to Mrs. Rockefeller by her husband during his travels.
  - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich - Letters to Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, 1933-1935 (Box 12, Folder 93)
  - Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker - Letters to Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1932-1936 (Box 12, Folder 94)
  - Rockefeller, John D., Jr. - Letters to/from Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, 1933-1956 (Box 12, Folder 95)
  - Rockefeller, John D., Jr. - Letters to Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, 1932-1957 (Box 12, Folder 96)
  - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd - Letters to Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, 1931-1932 (Box 12, Folder 97)
  - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd - Letters to Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, 1937, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 98)
  - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd - Letters from Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller - from Europe, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 99)
  - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd - Letters from Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller - from Asia, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 100)
  - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd - Letters from Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller - from Africa, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 101)
  - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd - Letters from Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller - from Latin America, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 102)
  - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd - Letters from Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller - from Japan, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 103)
  - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd - Letters from Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller - from Europe, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 104)
  - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd - Miscellaneous Papers, n.d., 1919, 1946-1949 (Box 12, Folder 105)
  - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd - Telegrams to/from Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, 1932, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 106)
  - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd - Gift/Flower Cards (Box 12, Folder 107)
  - Rockefeller, Mary Todhunter Clark, 1952-1991 (Box 12, Folder 108)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A. - Condolences on Death of, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 109)
- Subject Files, 1933-1994; 53/3; 16 Cubic Feet 40 Boxes
  Mrs. Rockefeller's personal papers as well as the files from the organizations for which she labored were maintained in one alphabetical subject sequence.
  Of a personal nature are records relating to Mrs. Rockefeller's art collection, debut, education, engagement, household maintenance, financial management, travels, and wedding. Her personal correspondence, which was maintained alphabetically, will also be found in this series (boxes 40 and 41). Of special note is a scrapbook containing photographs, invitations, brochures, newspaper clippings, and other ephemera and memorabilia documenting Mrs. Rockefeller's life prior to her engagement. (The scrapbook was separated from this series and placed in the Photographs series.) Also of interest are the files relating to her engagement (box 26) and wedding (boxes 50 through 52) to John D. Rockefeller 3rd. A letter and a drawing from Violet Oakley, a popular illustrator, muralist, and social activist, are part of the wedding files. Oakley, a friend of the Hooker family and a leading proponent of the League of Nations, presented a pen-and-ink drawing to the couple upon the occasion of their marriage (separated to Photographs series.)
  Also of a personal nature is the correspondence between Blanchette and John D. Rockefeller 3rd and members of the Rowntree family in England (boxes 43 and 44). Mr. and Mrs. Rockefeller agreed in 1940 to take Benjamin and David, two of the young sons of Peter and Bessie Rowntree, into their home until it was deemed safe for the boys to return to war-ravaged England. For four years the boys lived with the Rockefeller family. The letters offer insights into life on both sides of the Atlantic during World War II.
  The balance of the papers in this series reflects Mrs. Rockefeller's social concerns and philanthropic endeavors. Shortly after her marriage in 1932, Mrs. Rockefeller began her involvement in charitable and civic activities by joining the Central Council of the Community Service Society (see box 24). Throughout her marriage (and particularly after her children were grown), Mrs. Rockefeller served on committees and as a board member for a number of organizations as well as on a variety of governmental commissions and panels. Though numerous, Mrs. Rockefeller's involvement with these organizations and institutions was never casual. For example, in a November 1939 letter to the National Board of the YMCA (box 52) she gave a lengthy and thoughtful enumeration of her reasons for resigning from the board. Her efforts would be whole-hearted or not at all. This series documents the dedication of Mrs. Rockefeller and the scope of her contributions (of both time and money) to a variety of organizations and agencies, including the Asia Society, Japan Society, Lincoln Center, and the New York State Council on the Arts.
  Moving Images
  - Agricultural Development Council, 1980-1983 (Box 13, Folder 110)
  - American Assembly, 1974-1975 (Box 13, Folder 111)
  - American Association of Museums, (1975-1986)-1991 (Box 13, Folder 112)
  - American Red Cross - Pocantico Hills War Relief Committee, 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 113)
  - American Red Cross - Courses, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 114)
  - Appointment Books and Desk Diaries, 1947, 1949, 1950; 3 items (Box 13, Folder 115)
  - Appointment Books and Desk Diaries, 1973-1979; 10 volumes (Box 14, Folder 115A)
  - Appointment Books and Desk Diaries, 1979-1992; 26 volumes (Box 15, Folder 115B)
  - Archives of American Art - Oral History, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 116)
  - Arts - Arts and Business Council (New York City), 1976-1988 (Box 16, Folder 117)
  - Arts - Business Committee for the Arts, 1979-1983 (Box 16, Folder 118)
  - Arts - The Municipal Art Society, 1981-1983 (Box 16, Folder 119)
  - Asia Society - Correspondence, 1959, 1961, (1978-1992) (Box 16, Folder 120)